Guide to the Nancy Ottmann Albert Papers, 1981 - 2006
Nancy Ottmann Albert Papers1981 - 2006
- Series II. Negatives
  - Binder 4: Negative book 4, 1998-1999
    - 9937 September, 1999; CT: Portland, Middletown; roadside vernacular; truck along Rte. 17 (Binder 1)
    - 9938 September, 1999; CT: East Windsor area; roadside vernacular, along Rte. 5 (Binder 1)
    - 9939 September 26, 1999; CT: Thompsonville, Glastonbury; roadside vernacular; *steam shovel along Rte. 17 (Binder 1)
    - 9940 September 29, 1999; CT: Middletown, Thomaston; waterworks, housing projects, LRV, Thomaston dam (Binder 1)
    - 9941 September 29, 1999; CT: Thomaston, Colebrook; waterworks, rural vernacular; Thomaston dam (Binder 1)
    - 9942 October 6, 1999; CT: Middletown; housing projects, Long River Village (Binder 1)
    - 9943 October 13, 1999; CT: Middletown; housing projects, LRV (Binder 1)
    - 9944 October 1999; CT: Middletown; mills, housing projects, Crittenden Mfg. LRV (Binder 1)
    - 9945 October 22, 1999; CT: Hartford; CT River, mills; Riverfront, Colt Factory (Binder 1)
    - 9946 October 22, 1999; CT: Hartford, MA: Hatfield; CT Rover, roadside vernacular, *Founder's Bridge, gas pumps (Binder 1)
    - 9947 October 22, 1999; MA: Hatfield, Greenfield; roadside, urban vernacular, gas pumps, bank (Binder 1)
    - 9949 October 23, 1999; MA: Fitchburg area; milltowns, *some good images (Binder 1)
    - 9948 October 23, 1999; MA: Hubbardston, Fitchburg; houses, roadside vernacular, *houses with bittersweet (Binder 1)
    - 9950 October 23, 1999; MA: Fitchburg, NH: Newmarket; Milltowns, textile mills, Salmon River Mills (Binder 1)
    - 9951 October 23-24, 1999; NH: Newmarket, MA: Lawrence; milltowns, textile mills (Binder 1)
    - 9952 October, 1999; MA: Lawrence, CT: Middletown; textile mills, housing projects, *good shots of mills along river (Binder 1)
    - 9953 November 8, 1999; CT: Middletown; housing projects, LRV-the end of the houses (Binder 1)
    - 9954 November 11, 1999; CT: Middletown; housing projects, LRV-the stack (Binder 1)
    - 9955 November 16, 1999; CT: Middletown; mental hospitals, CVH-damaged roll (Binder 1)
    - 9956 November 16, 1999; CT: Middletown; mental hospitals, *CVH-interior shots (Binder 1)
    - 9957 November 16, 1999; CT: Middletown; mental hospitals, CVH interiors (Binder 1)
    - 9958 November, 1999; CT: Middletown; mental hospitals, CVH, Middletown river area (Binder 1)
    - CVH November, 1999 (Binder 1)
      1 sheet, 35 negatives
    - 9959 December 30, 1999; CT: Middletown, MA: Southwick; housing projects, rural vernacular, LRV as barren site (Binder 1)
    - 9960 December 30, 1999; MA: Southwick; rural vernacular, abandoned farmstead (Binder 1)
  - Binder 5: Negative book 5, 2000-2002
    - 0001 June, 2000; ME: St. John River valley; rural vernacular, Madawaska area (Binder 1)
    - 0002 June, 2000; ME and NB: St. John River area; rural vernacular; *double barns (Binder 1)
    - 0003 June, 2000; ME: Lille area; churches, rural vernacular (Binder 1)
    - 0004 June-July, 2000; ME, CT: Waterford; rural vernacular, greenhouses, Northern ME, Harkness (Binder 1)
    - 0005 July, 2000; CT: Portland, Rocky Hill; mills, greenhouses, along CT River (Binder 1)
    - 0006 July, 2000; CT, MA: Northwest area, Granville houses, roadside vernacular, *great images of farmhouse (Binder 1)
    - 0007 July, 2000; NY: Hyde Park, MA: Winchendon; roadside vernacular, mills (Binder 1)
    - 0008 July, 2000; MA: Winchendon, NH: Concord; roadside, mental hospitals, *field of toilets, car (Binder 1)
    - 0009 July, 2000; NH: Concord, ME: Kenneybunk; mental hospitals, Concord State Hospital (Binder 1)
    - 0010 August, 2000; NH: Hillsborough, CT: Middletown; textile mills, mental hospitals, *Hillsborough mill site, CVH (Binder 1)
    - 0011 August, 2000; CT: Middletown, NY: Brooklyn; bridges, urban architecture, CVH, Brooklyn Bridge (Binder 1)
    - 0012 August, 2000; NY: Brooklyn, CT: Baltic; bridges, textile mills, *Brooklyn and Manhattan Bridges (Binder 1)
    - 0013 August, 2000; CT: New London, MA: Adams; urban vernacular, roadside, Whitcomb Summit cabins (Binder 1)
    - 0014 Aug-Oct. 2000; MA: Rte. 2, NH: Enfield; roadside vernacular, cabins, Mascoma Lake, Enfield NH (Binder 1)
    - 0015 October, 2000; NH: Franklin; roadside vernacular, rusting machinery at freight yard (Binder 1)
    - 0016 October, 2000; NH: Franklin area; bridges, mills, *RR bridge-good images (Binder 1)
    - 0017 October, 2000; NH: Pennacook area; mills, churches, high contrast negatives (Binder 1)
    - 0018 October 14, 2000; VT: hartland, Springfield; waterworks, mills, CT River, very bright day (Binder 1)
    - 0019 October 14, 2000; VT: Bellows Falls; roadside vernacular, bridges, Santa's Land-very thin negs. (Binder 1)
    - 0020 CT: Middletown, Middlefield; November, 2000; houses, roadside vernacular, Russell House, quonsethut (Binder 1)
    - 0021 November, 2000; CT: Middlefield, Haddam; roadside vernacular; fruit stand, Shad Shack (Binder 1)
    - 0022 November 2000; CT: Madison; roadside vernacular, airport, Griswold Airport, abandoned planes (Binder 1)
    - 0101 January, 2001; CT: Middlefield, Portland; rural and roadside vernacular, steam shovel, Lyman's Orchard (Binder 1)
    - 0102 Feb-March, 2001; CT: Berlin, Hartford; churches, Bushnell Park; Worthington Mtg. House (Binder 1)
    - 0103 March 18, 2001; Cuba: Havana; urban architecture, people, *domino players, street scenes (Binder 1)
    - 0104 March 18, 2003; Cuba: Havana; architecture, people, *along the Malecon (Binder 1)
    - 0105 March 18, 2001; Cuba: Havana; architecture, Plaza Vieja (Binder 1)
    - 0106 March 19, 2001; Cuba: Havana; architecture, people; *Plaza Vieja, inside a solare (Binder 1)
    - 0107 March 20, 2001; Cuba: Havana; architecture, Necropolis, Vedado area (Binder 1)
    - 0108 March 20, 2001; Cuba: Havana; urban vernacular; Santeria site (Binder 1)
    - 0109 March 20, 2001; Cuba: Havana; architecture, street scenes, *fisherman, El Capitolio (Binder 1)
    - 0110 March 21, 2001; Cuba: Havana; architecture, street scenes, Centro Habana, arcades (Binder 1)
    - 0111 March 21, 2001; Cuba: Havana; street scenes, Avenida Reina (problem negatives) (Binder 1)
    - 0112 March 21, 2001; Cuba: Havana; Architecture, people, Centro Habana (Binder 1)
    - 0113 March 21, 2001; Cuba: Havana; architecture, parks, children, *Avenida Cinco, Banyon trees (Binder 1)
    - 0114 March 22, 2001; Cuba: Havana; people, dancers, *women at market (Binder 1)
    - 0115 March 23, 2001; Cuba: Cojumar; vernacular, people, shoe shine (Binder 1)
    - 0116 March 23, 2001; Cuba: Cojimar; vernacular, people, peanut seller, man painting (Binder 1)
    - 0117 March 23, 2001; Cuba: Cojimar, Havana; architecture, street scenes, high contrast negatives (Binder 1)
    - 0118 March-April 2001; Cuba: Havana, CT: Bloomfield; *architecture, people, women in doorway, CIGNA Bld. (Binder 1)
    - 0119 April-May 2001; CT: Bloomfield, Glastonbury; architecture, roadside vernacular, CIGNA-Wilde Bld., aong Rte. 17 (Binder 1)
    - 0120 June 3, 2001; CT: Middletown, Willimantic;mental hospitals, mills, CVH, Frog Bridge (Binder 1)
    - 0121 June, 2001; CT: Mansfield, NS: Argyle; mental hospitals, churches, Mansfield Training Center (Binder 1)
    - 0122 June 18-19, 2001; NS: Peggy's Cove area; churches, boars, *B and W churhces, boats/reflections (Binder 1)
    - 0123 June 20-21, 2001; NS: Cape Breton, Maitland; rural and roadside vernacular; **motel, storefront, church in field (Binder 1)
    - 0124 June 22, 2003; NS, ME; churches, rural vernacular, *farmstead, house, Rte. 1 ME (Binder 1)
    - 0125 July, 2001; MA: Hatfield, VT, NH; roadside vernacular, mills, gas pumps, Rte. 5, Brattleboro mill (Binder 1)
    - 0126 July, 2001; VT: Graniteville, NH: Chelsea; quarries, roadside vernacular, *Chelesea house (Binder 1)
    - 0127 July 2001; NH: Chelsea, MA: Bernardson; houses, roadside vernacular, *Chelsea house, motel (Binder 1)
    - 0128 July-Aug 2001; MA: Bernardston, VT: Brattleboro; houses, railroads, Ostey Organ housing, train cars (Binder 1)
    - 0129 Sept. 15-16, 2001; CT: New Haven, Stafford Springs; urban and roadside vernacular, movie house, hardware store (Binder 1)
    - 0130 Sept. 16, 2001; CT: N. Grosvenordale area; houses, milltowns, Roseland Cottage (Binder 1)
    - 0131 Setp. 2001; CT: NGD, Middletown; houses, milltowns, working housing, Russell House (Binder 1)
    - 0132 October 7, 2001; RI: Cranston; mental hospitals, *Howard Center (Binder 1)
    - 0133 October 7, 2001; RI: Cranston; mental hospitals, *Howard Center (Binder 1)
    - 0134 October 7, 2001; RI: Pontiac, CT: Brooklyn; textile mills, houses, Pontiac Mill (Binder 1)
    - 0135 October 2001; CT: Middletown, GA: Athens area; roadside vernacular, houses, *gas pumps, Russell House (Binder 1)
      1 sheet,15 negatives
    - 0236 October, 2001; NC: Charlotte area; roadside vernacular, motels, high contrast negatives (Binder 1)
    - 0237 Oct.-Nov., 2001; NC: Charlotte, CT: Baltic; urban and rurall vernacular; signs on buildings, oil tanks (Binder 1)
    - 0138 November, 2001; CT: Baltic, Middletown; Mills, CT River; Baltic Mill, Arrigoni Bridge (Binder 1)
    - 0140 November 2001; CT: Middletown; institutions, Long Lane School, gas pumps (Binder 1)
    - 0139 November 2001; CT: Middletown; institutions, Long Lane School (Binder 1)
    - 0201 Jan.-March 2002; CT: Haddam, VA: Winchester; roadside vernacular, bridges; Shad Shack, New London bridge, motel (Binder 1)
    - 0202 March 2002; VA: Winchester, SC; storefronts, roadside vernacular, *gas station, SC (Binder 1)
    - 0203 March 2002; SC: Charleston area, CT: Mdtn. Houses; *SC mansion interior, R. House (Binder 1)
    - 0204 June 2002; MA: Winchendon and Ware, ME; roadside vernacular, mills; abandoned car, Ware and Saco mills (Binder 1)
    - 0205 June 2002; ME: Topsham, Berwick; bridges, mills, houses, along Rte. 1 (Binder 1)
    - 0206 June-July 2002; ME: Bucksport, CT: Middletown; urban and rural vernacular; Grand Theater, St. John's school (Binder 1)
    - 0208 July-Aug. 2002; CT: Middletown, Collinsville; bridges, milltowns; Arrigini Bridge, waterworks (Binder 1)
    - 0207 August, 2002; CT: Collinsville, Granby; bridges, vernacular, architecture, barns, CIGNA Bld. (HRJ) (Binder 1)
    - 0209 Sept. 2002; CT: Bloomfield, MA: Deerfield; architecture; Wilde Bld. (HRJ) barns, town hall (Binder 1)
    - 0210 Sept. 2002; MA: Deerfield, CT: Hartford; houses, architecture; *roadside lighthouse, Polish Home (HRJ) (Binder 1)
    - 0211 November 2002; CT: Bloomfield, Wethersfield; architecture, bridges; Emhart Bld. (HRJ) Rte. 3 bridge (Binder 1)
    - 0212 Dec. 2002; CT: Middletown, Hartford; institutions, theaters, Long Lane School, Webster Theater (HRJ) (Binder 1)
  - Binder 6: Negative book 6, 2003
    - 0301 January 2003; FL: St. Augustine; roadside and urban vernacular; *good images, gate, storefront (Binder 1)
    - 0302 January 2003; FL: St. Augustine; houses, roadside vernacular, high contrast (Binder 1)
    - 0303 January 2003; FL: St. Augustine; houses, vernacular, high contrast (Binder 1)
    - 0304 January 2003; FL: St. Augustine; houses, Lincolnville area (Binder 1)
    - 0306 March 2003; NH: Claremont area; milltowns, bridges, high contrast, snow (Binder 1)
    - 0307 March 9, 2003; VT: Bellows Falls, Brattleboro; CT River, milltowns, *good images, high contrast (Binder 1)
    - 0305 March 2003; NH: Claremont area; houses, milltowns, snow scenes, high contrast (Binder 1)
    - 0308 March 2003; NC: Charlotte, SC: Cheraw; houses, roadside vernacular, truck, auction (Binder 1)
    - 0309 March 2003; SC: Cheraw area; houses, urban vernacular; church window, barber shop (Binder 1)
    - 0310 March 22, 2003; SC: Cheraw; urban and rural vernacular; *abandoned schoolhouse (Binder 1)
    - 0311 March 22, 2003; SC: Cheraw area; roadside vernacular; *good images, storefronts (Binder 1)
    - 0312 April 2003; CT: Middletown, Hartford; roadside vernacular, huoses, Rte. 156, Colt factory houses (Binder 1)
    - 0313 May 2003; CT: Meriden, Middletown; urban streetscape, Russell House (Binder 1)
    - 0314 June 2003; NB: St. Andrews, PEI; houses, churches, house to be moved, Souris area (Binder 1)
    - 0315 June 2003; Quebec: Les Ils de la Madelaine; vernacular, churches, fishing shed, Les Graves (Binder 1)
    - 0316 June 2003; Les Ils de la Madelaine; seascapes, churches, fishing shed (Binder 1)
    - 0317 June 2003; Les Ils de la Medelaine; cabins, seascape, vernacular, lighthouse, some good images (Binder 1)
    - 0318 June 2003; Les Ils de la Madelaine; boats, houses, *good images (Binder 1)
    - 0319 June 2003; Les Ils de la Madelaine; houses, boats, *good images, house with boat (Binder 1)
    - 0320 June 2003; Les Ils de la Madelaine, PEI; houses, churches, cabins, *fishing shacks, PEI bridge (Binder 1)
    - 0321 June 2003; ME, along Rte. 1, MA; houses, roadside vernacular, includes motels, diner (Binder 1)
    - 0322 July 2003; NY: Hudson Valley; houses, roadside vernacular, good porches, details (Binder 1)
    - 0323 July 2003; NY: Bard College, Hudson; architecture, houses, Performing Arts Center (Binder 1)
    - 0324 August 2003; MA: Boston; bridges, "Big Dig" project (Binder 1)
    - 0325 August 2003; CT: Hartford, Willimantic; textile mills, diners, Willimantic Thread, Hog River Diner (Binder 1)
    - 0326 August-September 2003; CT: Willimantic, Hartford; houses, bridges, CT River, Hartford, damages roll (Binder 1)
    - 0327 Sept 26, 2003; CT: Hartford, Suffield; CT: River, bridges, bright day (Binder 1)
    - 0328 September-October 2003; CT: Suffield, Vienna; houses, architecture, Palm Haus, Votive Kirke (Binder 1)
    - 0329 October 2003; Vienna; architecture, churches, *Belvedere, Karlsplatz station (Binder 1)
    - 0330 October 2003; Vienna; parks, streetscenes, Riesenard, Prater (Binder 1)
    - 0331 October 2003; Vienna; parks, technology, *Riesenrad, Prater (Binder 1)
    - 0332 October 2003; Vienna; architecture, technology, *gasometers, Otto Wagner station (Binder 1)
    - 0333 October 2003; Vienna (Schoenbrunn); architecture, *Palmhaus, RR Station (Binder 1)
    - 0334 October 2003; Vienna (Heitzig); parks, architecture, *Schoenbrunn, Palmhaus (Binder 1)
    - 0335 October 2003; Vienna (Heitzig); houses, architecture, Heitzig houses, passageways (Binder 1)
    - 0336 October-November 2003; Vienna, VT: St. Johnsbury; architecture, roadside vernacular, *abandoned bus (Binder 1)
    - 0337 November 2003; VT: St. Johnsbury area; roadside vernacular, bridges, wood buildings, warehouse, trains (Binder 1)
  - Binder 7: Negative book 7, 2004-2005
    - 0338-0401 Nov. 2003-Jan. 2004; NH: Keane, CT: Old Lyme; rural vernacular, rivers, Keane area barn, Lieutenant River (Binder 1)
    - 0402 January 2004; CT: Old Saybrook; rivers, bridges, railroad bridge near Old Saybrook (Binder 1)
    - 0403 March 2004; NY: Garden City; architecture, St. Paul's School (Binder 1)
    - 0404 March 2004; MA: Holyoke; urban vernacular; very thin negatives (Binder 1)
    - 0405 March, 2004; MA: Holyoke; urban vernacular, mills, thin negativesm good shot of canal (Binder 1)
    - 0406 March 2004; MA: Holyoke, Springfield; urban streets, tenementsl; thin negatives (Binder 1)
    - 0407 April 2004; CT: Old Lyme, Middletown; rural and roadside vernacular; *New Dawn Dairy, abandoned car (Binder 1)
    - 0408 April 2004; CT: Newington, RI: Watch Hill; motels and hotels, Berlin Tpke., *Ocean House (Binder 1)
    - 0409 April 2004; RI: Watch Hill; hotels, *Ocean House (Binder 1)
    - 0410 May 2004; CT: Mystic area, NH: Manchester; water, vernacular, houses, Stonington, Manchester houses (Binder 1)
    - 0411 May 2004; NH: Manchester; mills, rivers, bridges, Amoskaeg complez (Binder 1)
    - 0412 May 2004; NH, VT: Bridgewater; rural vernacular, water, along Rte. 100 (Binder 1)
    - 0413 May 2004; VT: Weston, Brattleboro; rural vernacular, hospitals; Brattleboro Asylum (Binder 1)
    - 0414 May 2004; ME: Ogunquit; roadside vernacular, motels, *cabins in Ogunquit (Binder 1)
    - 0415 July 2004; NB, QC, Canada; vernacular, hospitals, 8Grosse Ile Site (Binder 1)
    - 0416 July 2004; Quebec: Grosse Ile; hospitals, cemeteries, *excellent images (Binder 1)
    - 0417 July 2004; Quebec: Grosse Ile; hospitals, urban street scenes, some interiors (Binder 1)
    - 0418 July 2004; Quebec: Montreal; urban and industrial architecture, old port, high contrast negatives (Binder 1)
    - 0419 July 2004; Montreal, VT: Rte. 2; waterfront, rural vernacular, harbor, old railroad station (Binder 1)
    - 0420 July 2004; VT: along Rte. 7; rural vernacular; *truck, hay for sale (Binder 1)
    - 0421 July, August 2004; VT, CT: Harkness Park; roadside vernacular, cabins, greenhouses (Binder 1)
    - 0422 August 2004; MA: Cambridge, Boston; urban architecture, Gehry building at MIT (Binder 1)
    - 0423 August 2004; MA: Boston, Holyoke; waterfront, urban streetscape; *ruined fort (Binder 1)
    - Unmarked Negatives (Binder 1)
    - 0425 November 2004; Barcelona; urban architecture, Casa Milla, stairway, roof (Binder 1)
    - 0426 November 2004; Barcelona; churches, cloister, romanesque church (Binder 1)
    - 0427 November 2004; Barcelona; streetscenes, churches, Bari Gothic, Ribera (Binder 1)
    - 0428 November 2004; Barcelona; churches, parks, *Parc de la Ciudad (Binder 1)
    - 0429 November 2004; Barcelona; architecture, parks, *Parc de Pedrables (Binder 1)
    - 0430 November 2004; Barcelona; churches, architecture, *Monestir and Parc Pedrables (Binder 1)
    - 0431 November 2004; Barcelona; parks, architecture, *Parc Gurll, La Pedrera (Binder 1)
    - 0433 Dec. 29-30, 2004; CT: Middletown; rivers, institutions, CT River, Long Lane (overdeveloped negs.) (Binder 1)
    - 0434 Dec. 30-31, 2004; CT: Middletown; institutions, Long Lane School (Binder 1)
    - 0501 January 2005; CT: Middletown; institutions, *Long Lane School (Binder 1)
    - 0502 February 13, 2005; VT: Rutland area; roadside vernacular, motels, *good images, high contrast snow (Binder 1)
    - 0503 February 13, 2005; VT: Rutland area; waterpower, Milltowns, high contrast (Binder 1)
    - 0504 Feb. 14, 2005; VT: Rockinhgham, Brattleboro; churches, roadside vernacular, high contrast, snow (Binder 1)
    - 0506 March 21, 22, 2005; TN: Nashville; rivers, urban vernacular, downtown Nashville (Binder 1)
    - 0507 April 2005; CT, Norwich area; barns, milltowns, *abandoned gas station (Binder 1)
    - 0508 April 2005; CT: Norwhich, Middletown; roadside vernacular, *gas stations, old car (Binder 1)
    - 0509 May 2005; CT: Middletown; institutions, *Long Lane School (Binder 1)
    - 0510 June 2005; CT: Middletown, NC, VA; institutions, roadside vernacular, Long Lane, abandoned barns in VA (Binder 1)
    - 0511 June 2005; CT: Harkness, Middletown; greenhouses, institutions, *greenhouse at Harkness (Binder 1)
    - 0512 July 2005; CT: Middletown; institutions, Long Lane, thin negatives (Binder 1)
    - 0513 July 2005; NH: south and east of Grantham; mental hospitals, roadside vernacular, *poor farm, truck in field (Binder 1)
    - 0514 July 2005; NH: Franklin, ME: S. Berwick; roadside vernacular, mills, R.R cars, mill pond, garage (Binder 1)
    - 0514 July 2005; ME: S. Berwick, NH: southeast area; cabins, mills, lakeside cabins, quonset hut garage (Binder 1)
    - 0515 August 2005; CT: Granby, Torrington, Winsted; diners, roadside vernacular; *Skee's, hotdog man (Binder 1)
    - 0516 September 2006; CT: Middletown, Brooklyn; diners, institutions, churches, Long Lane demolition, Brooklyn church (Binder 1)
    - 0517 Sept.-Dec. 2005; CT: Brooklyn, Dayville area; roadside vernacular, churches, drive-in, Brooklyn church (Binder 1)
    - Envelope of Long Lane Negatives; 1 print each, entire roll (Binder 1)
      19 negative strips
- Series III. Slides
  - Binder 8: Slides--Color and Black + White images
    - Mental Hospitals series--Fairfield Hills, Northampton, Norwich, CVH (B+W) (Binder 1)
      1 sheet, 20 slides
    - Mental Hospital Series, Northampton (1999) B+W (Binder 1)
    - Mental Hospital Series, Fairfield Hills, Northampton, CVH (Binder 1)
    - (Binder 1)
      1 sheet, 18 slides
    - Mental Hospital Series, All CVH (B+W) (Binder 1)
    - Older Vernacular Images, early 1990s (Binder 1)
    - Unmarked Sheet (Binder 1)
    - Slides Marked Individually (Binder 1)
      5 sheets, 96 slides
    - British + French Documentary Photography (Binder 1)
    - Eugene Atget, Paris (Binder 1)
    - Documentary Photography, Eugene Atget and Hartford Public Library (Binder 1)
      1 sheet, 15 slides
    - Vernacular 1999, mill towns, Baltic, NH Bridges (Binder 1)
      1 sheet, 19 slides
    - Mental Hospital Series B+W, Norwich Hospital (Binder 1)
    - hartford CT--mostly 1998-99, CT River Valley (Bellows Falls etc) (Binder 1)
      1 sheet, 17 slides
    - Documentary Photography Spendor, B. Abbott, R. Frank, E. Atget (Binder 1)
    - Documentary Photography, John davies, Diane Arbus, D. Lange (Binder 1)
    - Historic Images for Lectures, Lange, Fran W. Abbott (Binder 1)
    - American Documentary Photography, Abbott-Evans (Binder 1)
    - Documentary Photography Lewis Hine (Binder 1)
    - Historic Images for Lectures, Hine, Abbott, Lange (Binder 1)
    - Color-Baltic 1999-2000, Willimantic (Binder 1)
    - Color MASMOCA (Collinsville) Aug 1999 (Binder 1)
    - Color-Hartford 1999, Newmarket, NH (trip Fall) (Binder 1)
    - Color-Hartford, CT, Newmarket NH, 1999 (Binder 1)
    - Color-New Market NH, Lawrence MA 1999 (Binder 1)
    - Color-Willimantic 2000 (Binder 1)
    - Western CT--mills, etc. (Binder 1)
    - Unmarked Sheet (Binder 1)
  - Binder 9 (black binder)
    - France 1991-94, some 1996, b+w (Binder 1)
    - France 1996 (b+w) (Binder 1)
    - France 1996 (Binder 1)
    - France 1994 (Binder 1)
    - France 1994, Avignon (Binder 1)
    - Unmarked Slides (Binder 1)
      1 sheet, 10 slides
    - Unmarked Slides (Binder 1)
    - Vacation Slides 1997-99 (Binder 1)
    - Unmarked Slides (Binder 1)
      some slides individually marked, include: Lisbon (1), Balum (7), Marfa (2), Obidas (1), Obidas Estrugon de Convento (1)
    - Unmarked Slides (Binder 1)
      2 slides marked individually: Obidas (2)
    - Unmarked Slides (Binder 1)
      some slides marked individually: Busaco (2), Marfau (8)
    - (Binder 1)
      some slides marked individually: Marfau (2), Maruao (8)
    - Unmarked Slides (Binder 1)
      some slides marked individually: Evora March 1997 (1), Evora (2), Maruoa (1), Pousada-Evora (1)
    - Unmarked Slides (Binder 1)
      1 slide marked Evora-Roll 4
    - Unmarked Slides (Binder 1)
      1 sheet, 6 slides
    - Unmarked Slides (Binder 1)
      2 slides marked Madrid
    - Unmarked Slides (Binder 1)
      4 slides marked Bourgos
    - Spain-March, 1998, Bourgos-Bilbao (Binder 1)
    - Unmarked Slides (Binder 1)
      some slides marked individually: Bilbao (2), Santillana del Mar (1)
    - Unmarked Slides (Binder 1)
      some slides marked individually: Santillana (3), Altamira (1)
    - Unmarked Slides (Binder 1)
      some slides marked individually: Gaudi (1), Seqovia (3)
    - Unmarked Slides (Binder 1)
      2 slides marked Segovia
    - Unmarked Slides (Binder 1)
      sonme slides marked individually: Seqovia (1), Avila (2), Madrid (2)
    - Unmarked Slides (Binder 1)
      1 slide marked Madrid
    - Bermuda-Christmas 1998 (Binder 1)
      2 sheets, 39 slides
    - Bermuda Dec. 1998 (Binder 1)
      2 sheets, 36 slides
- Series IV. Photographs
  - Binder 11: 5" x 7" research photos for New England Mill Project, 1981-1984 (Binder 1)
    - Arctic Mill, Arctic (West Warwick) RI R-A-3 (Binder 1)
      2 photos
    - Carolina, RI R-C-1 (Binder 1)
      10 photos
    - Unmarked photos (Binder 1)
    - Central Falls, RI, R-C-2 (Binder 1)
      5 photos
      5th photo found within R-P-2 series
    - Chepachet, RI, R-C-3 (Binder 1)